NEIL ALVAREZ GARCIA

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL RESUME

I am a Full-Stack Developer with three years of experience, who is constantly striving to learn and improve both professionally and personally. I enjoy challenging myself with emerging technologies and staying up to date with the latest trends in the industry.

PROFESSIONAL HABILITIES

FRONT-END:

HTML5, CSS3 (Bootstrap, tailwind and SASS), JAVASCRIPT, TYPESCRIPT, REACT.JS, NEXTJS

BACK-END:

TYPESCRIPT, NODEJS, EXPRESS, GRAPHQL, MONGODB, MYSQL, POSTGRESQL, FIREBASE

MOBILE:

REACT-NATIVE

ANOTHER TECHNOLOGIES:

DOCKER, GIT, TESTING WITH JEST

OTHER SKILLS:

ENGLISH, SPANISH, GOOD WORKING AT A TEAM AND UNDER PRESURE, LEADERSHIP, MENTORING, FAST AND SELF LEARNER

CONTACT ME

Email: **Neil8b.jjr2014@gmail.com** Cellphone: **+57-3024151956**

EXPERIENCES

SOFTWARE FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Phantom technology | December 2023 - Current

I am responsible for creating features, review code, assisting others, and fixing any bug that comes along in the development. I work closely with the front-end, and backend teams to ensure move along with the development:

- I take the design and convert it into code, giving the result expected, as per page.
- I create entire features, keeping good structure and clean code, along with a fast development.
- I fix and debug errors that encounter along in the development, to deliver well tested user interfaces.

SOFTWARE FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Quchara | January 2023 - December 2023

I was responsible for creating the mvp, leading the frontend team, review code, assisting others, and fixing any bug that comes along in the development. I worked closely with the design, front-end, and backend teams to ensure that we deliver a high-quality product at a fast pace.

- I started from scratch the mpv to allow users to order their lunch without any hassle that comes with ordering and delivering food.
- I helped with the backend development to ensure that we address any issues that arise during the development.
- I migrated the entire frontend to a new design, applying clean code, well and structure code along with good practices.

SOFTWARE FRONTEND DEVELOPER

GreenRun | April 2020 to November 2022

With the design, frontend, and QA teams, I was in charge of creating, improving, and fixing the app that GreenRun offers to users for betting.

- I integrated a new library into the app, improving its loading time and reducing its weight.
- I created a web app from scratch that allowed influencers to create links for current bets, which they could share with their followers. This helped improve the number of users who were betting.
- I created different widgets for the app, upgrading and improving the user experience of the application.

ACADEMIC TRAINING

VIRTUAL COURSES, FORUMS AND DOCUMENTATIONS

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

-HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, tailwind and SASS

-JAVASCRIPT, TYPESCRIPT

-React.js, Nextjs

-React native

-Nodejs, Express, Graphql

-MongoDB, Mysql, Postgresql

-Jest and Unit Testing

-Git and Docker - English